Unforgotten, forever loved and adored.
Evita is a history, drama film directed by Alan Parker.
The hit musical based on the life of Evita Duarte, an Argentinian actress who eventually became the wife
of Argentinian president Juan Perón, and the most beloved and hated woman in Argentina.
Eva Perón, played by Madonna.
Ché, played by Antonio Banderas.
Juan Perón, played by Jonathan Pryce.
Agustín Magaldi, played by Jimmy Nail.
Doña Juana, played by Victoria Sus.
Brother Juan, played by Julian Littman.
Evita is a 1996 American biographical musical drama film based on the 1978 stage musical by Tim
Rice and Andrew Lloyd Webber, which itself originated as a 1976 concept album.
Directed by Alan Parker from a screenplay he co-wrote with Oliver Stone, the film depicts the life of Argentine
actress-turned-politician Eva Perón, detailing her beginnings, rise to power, and untimely death.
It stars Madonna in the title role, with Jonathan Pryce as her husband Juan Perón and
Antonio Banderas as Ché, an everyman who serves as the film's narrator.
A film adaptation of the musical languished in development for over fifteen years, as rights
passed on to several major studios, and various directors and actors considered.
In 1993, producer Robert Stigwood sold the rights to Andrew G.
Vajna, who agreed to finance the film through his production company Cinergi Pictures,
with Buena Vista Pictures distributing the film through Hollywood Pictures.
After Stone stepped down from the project in 1994,
Parker agreed to write and direct the film.
Recording sessions for the songs and soundtrack took place at CTS
Studios in London, roughly four months before filming.
Parker worked with Rice and Lloyd Webber to compose the soundtrack,
reworking the music and lyrics to the original songs.
They also wrote a new song, "You Must Love Me", for the film.
Principal photography commenced in February 1996
and concluded in May of that year.
Filming took place on locations in Buenos Aires and Budapest as
well as on soundstages at Shepperton Studios.
The film's production in Argentina was met with controversy, as the cast and crew
faced protests over fears that the project would tarnish Eva's image.
Evita premiered at the Shrine Auditorium in Los
Angeles, California, on December 14, 1996.
Hollywood Pictures gave the film a platform release, which involved releasing it in
select cities before expanding distribution in the following weeks.
The film had a limited release on December 25, 1996,
before opening nationwide on January 10, 1997.
It grossed $141 million worldwide against a $55 million budget and received mixed reviews; while Madonna's performance, the
music, costume designs, and cinematography were praised, criticism was aimed at the pacing and direction.
Evita received numerous accolades, including the Academy Award for Best Original Song (for "You Must Love Me"), and three Golden Globe Awards:
Best Motion Picture – Comedy or Musical, Best Original Song ("You Must Love Me"), and Best Actress – Comedy or Musical (Madonna).
The film explores themes of prostitute, funeral,
narration, buenos aires, argentina, politician.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.